Okay, what up y'all? We're back with a
brand new video. Make sure you like and
subscribe if you appreciate the content.
Uh today we're going over my uh scale
two workflow. Uh scale two came out like
a month and a half ago at this point. Um
but it's like one of the best, if not
the best, motion control pipeline models
out there. Um
I would say it's better than one
animate. Uh or I would say not
necessarily better, but it has different
use cases. So, for dances, for uh lip
syncing and stuff like that, I would say
scale is significantly better.
Um but yeah, I'll go over the workflow.
I'm going to release this for free for
everybody. There is already a
sub version that I released on school.
Uh if you want to grab the free version,
just go on school and I'll grab that. Um
I'll have a post in there.
And if you want to get access to the
motion control reference pack with 1,300
uh videos like this one here. Um
that's for the sub, so just go on school
sub and you'll get access to that in the
classroom. Um for the workflow itself,
it's pretty simple. There's nothing too
crazy when it comes to the settings and
everything.
Um
you only have two inputs to take care
of. You need your reference image, so
that's going to be your influencer
usually, and then you need your
reference videos. Um 1,300 in the pack
right here.
And uh that's the only thing you really
need, right? Um
the frame rate of your video is going to
be set here. Uh you can leave it at 24.
For most people, that's going to be
fine. Uh you can turn it up to 30, but
it's going to generate more frames and
it's going to be slower. So, you just
take that into account. Um
and then when it comes to the actual
settings, so here for the LORAs, uh we
use a four-step LORA. We don't do 40
steps or whatever the [__] We We do not
do that. We use four steps. Uh that's a
character Laura trained on 1 to 2.2 low
noise. It should work fine. Um but
you'll have to test your your own and
see if it works, right? Uh this Laura, I
mean, I'm going to let you uh figure out
what it does, but I mean, it's pretty
obvious. Uh and this is just for extra
detail. I'll put the links to every
model and Laura you need in uh the
school post. Just grab that over there
and you should be good.
Uh then I'll go over to the video
resolution. So, here you can just choose
your res. Uh those are presets I made
for you guys. Um
For the sake of this video today, I'm
going to use the medium res, but you can
go higher, right? Um the higher you go,
obviously, the the longer it's going to
take to generate and the higher amount
of VRAM you'll need. Um
On the 5090, I'm using 24 gigs of VRAM
on the medium res here.
Uh but obviously, if you have a lot of
RAM, like I have a 128, you can offload
a lot of um the model on RAM and you
might be able to go higher res.
Um but you'll have to try it, obviously.
I can't try every single um
you know,
How do you say that? Every single
configuration cuz I only have one
configuration, right? Uh then we go over
to the tracking here. Um that's going to
be where the mask is created for the
video. Uh here you can see we have
female in, uh but if you want to do a
car replacement or a horse replacement
or whatever, can just change the word
here and make sure you have uh you know,
an appropriate uh reference image there
and you should be good. Um
Then, uh so this workflow will generate
uh your full video. So, if you in
upload uh 15-second video here, the
workflow is going to process every
single frame and give you a 15-second
video at the end.
I know a lot of workflows are limited to
5 or 10 seconds, but this one is going
to run the full video.
So, it's basically infinite.
So, yeah, I hope you guys enjoyed that.
And then, if you go here specifically,
so this is going to be the first run,
and then this run here is going to loop
until
the workflow is done and the video is
fully processed.
So,
that's it basically for the workflow. As
you can see, you only need to input two
things, and the rest should be done
automatically.
This is the result from
doing your replacement here.
And I'm going to run it now with the
still version.
The still version is essentially going
to take the movement from your reference
video and apply it on
your reference image. So, I'm just going
to run that here.
Tac.
And
yeah, I just I'll just wait for it to be
done and I'll be back after. But that's
pretty much it.
And
there's also the sub version of this
workflow that I already released.
I think it's this one here. And with
that, you'll be able to basically
generate your image
from the get-go and pass it directly to
the scale pipeline and get your final
result
directly in the workflow. [music]
I won't be showing too much cuz I think
there's some Nazi frog [__] over there,
but
that's just kind of the idea.
You generate your image and you pass it
directly in the scale instead of doing
it in two steps, right? That's kind of
the idea there.
And uh yeah, that's pretty much it. Um
we're just going to wait for that to be
done. Like you can see,
uh we're doing pretty good here.
Uh 6 second per iteration per step,
basically.
So,
let's see here.
Yeah, I'll just wait. BRB.
Okay, so we are done here. So, as you
can see, we took the movement from the
reference video and we applied it on our
um reference image.
Um so, yeah. That's pretty much it. As
you can see, it's it's a little bit
blurry, right? Uh but that's because we
used a pretty low res. We used a medium
res. If we used the highest res, this
should be pretty sharp. And um if you
use your character Laura, it's going to
be even better, I think.
So, that's pretty much the pipeline
here. If you have any questions, you
want to grab uh the reference uh control
pack, uh just sub on school. The
workflow will be free on school with all
the links and everything you need. And
uh yeah, I'm trying to get back into it
on the YouTube grind. So, um I'll be
making at least I'll try to make one
video a week or something like that just
to get back into it. And uh that's
pretty much it. Shout out to y'all.
Respect. And I'll see you in the next
one. Peace.